Every hero has a beginning.
Bumblebee is a action, adventure, science fiction
film directed by Travis Knight.
On the run in the year 1987, Bumblebee finds refuge in a
junkyard in a small Californian beach town.
Charlie, on the cusp of turning 18 and trying to find her place in the
world, discovers Bumblebee, battle-scarred and broken.
When Charlie revives him, she quickly learns this is no ordinary yellow VW bug.
B-127 / Bumblebee (voice), played by Dylan O'Brien.
Charlie Watson, played by Hailee Steinfeld.
Jack Burns, played by John Cena.
Memo Gutierrez, played by Jorge Lendeborg Jr..
Dr. Powell, played by John Ortiz.
Ron, played by Stephen Schneider.
Bumblebee (stylized as BumbleBee and sometimes marketed as Transformers: Bumblebee) is a
2018 science fiction action film based on the Transformers toy line character.
Directed by Travis Knight and written by Christina Hodson, it is the sixth
installment in the Transformers film series and a prequel to the 2007 film.
It stars Hailee Steinfeld, John Cena, Jorge Lendeborg Jr.,
John Ortiz, Jason Drucker, and Pamela Adlon.
Set in 1987, the film follows Bumblebee being sent to Earth for
refuge and befriending a teenage girl named Charlie.
The film premiered on December 3, 2018, at the Sony Center in Berlin, and was
released in the United States on December 21, by Paramount Pictures.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, who praised its action sequences,
Steinfeld's performance, Knight's direction, visuals, and the 1980s setting.
It was a box office success, grossing $468 million against a
production budget between $102–135 million.
It was followed by Transformers: Rise of the Beasts in June 2023.
The film explores themes of technology, based on toy,
robot, spin off, duringcreditsstinger.
The tone is thought_provoking.